<resources>
    <string name="app_name">My Application</string>
    <string name="title_activity_scrolling">ScrollingActivity</string>
    <string name="large_text">
        "Diabetes is a disease that occurs when your blood glucose, also called blood sugar, is too high.
        \n Blood glucose is your main source of energy and comes from the food you eat.
        \n Insulin, a hormone made by the pancreas, helps glucose from food get into your cells to be used for energy.
        \n Sometimes your body doesn’t make enough—or any—insulin or doesn’t use insulin well.
        \n Glucose then stays in your blood and doesn’t reach your cells.

Over time, having too much glucose in your blood can cause health problems.\n
Although diabetes has no cure, you can take steps to manage your diabetes and stay healthy.\n

Sometimes people call diabetes a touch of sugar or borderline diabetes.\n
These terms suggest that someone doesn’t really have diabetes or has a less serious case, but every case of diabetes is serious.\n

What health problems can people with diabetes develop?
Over time, high blood glucose leads to problems such as
        \n\n

heart disease\n
stroke\n
kidney disease\n
eye problems\n
dental disease\n
nerve damage\n
foot problems\n

\n\n
Here are some tips to help you reduce your risk of type 2 diabetes.\n

1> Check your risk of diabetes.\n Take the Life! risk assessment test and learn more about your risk of developing type 2 diabetes.\n A 12+ score indicates that you are at high risk and may be eligible for the Life! program - a free Victorian lifestyle modification program that helps you reduce your
risk of type 2 diabetes and cardiovascular disease, or call 13 RISK (13 7475).\n
\n\n
2> Manage your weight.\n Excess body fat, particularly if stored around the abdomen,
can increase the body’s resistance to the hormone insulin.\n This can lead to type 2 diabetes.\n
\n\n
3> Exercise regularly.\n Moderate physical activity on most days of the week helps manage weight, reduce blood glucose levels and may also improve blood pressure and cholesterol.\n
\n\n
4> Eat a balanced, healthy diet.\n Reduce the amount of fat in your diet, especially saturated and trans fats.\n Eat more fruit, vegetables and high-fibre foods.\n Cut back on salt.\n
\n\n
5> Limit takeaway and processed foods.\n ‘Convenience meals’ are usually high in salt, fat and kilojoules.\n It’s best to cook for yourself using fresh ingredients whenever possible.\n
\n\n
6> Limit your alcohol intake.\n Too much alcohol can lead to weight gain and may increase your blood pressure and triglyceride levels.\n Men should have no more than two standard drinks a day and women should have no more than one.\n
\n\n
7> Quit smoking.\n Smokers are twice as likely to develop diabetes as non-smokers.\n
\n\n
8> Control your blood pressure.\n Most people can do this with regular exercise, a balanced diet and by keeping a healthy weight.\n In some cases, you might need medication prescribed by your doctor.\n
\n\n
9> Reduce your risk of cardiovascular disease.\n Diabetes and cardiovascular disease have many risk factors in common, including obesity and physical inactivity.\n
\n\n
10> See your doctor for regular check-ups.\n As you get older, it’s a good idea to regularly check your blood glucose, blood pressure and blood cholesterol levels.\n"
        "
    </string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_information">information</string>
</resources>
